<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % allent SYSTEM "w3centities-f.ent">
%allent;
]>
<chapter version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
      
      <title>Roles</title>

      <para>
Great events are possible because great people are involved. Here you will find a listing and descrption for all of
the roles.
      </para>
      <para>
Roles that are needed for longer streaches of time are broken up into multiple shifts. Please pay attention to the
schedule and where your shift is on it. If you are having fun and want to keep working you are welcome to do that.
</para>

      <section>
            <title>A/V Guide</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnedemo
            </para>
            <para>
Part of providing a great demo comes from the confidence in understaning the A/V setup. The A/V Guide is there to
help the presenters understand the A/V setup and to help if something seems to be going wrong. Usually this role
is broken up into multiple shifts to cover the whole event. Before the event the A/V Guide works with the
presenters to make sure that they understand how to hook into the input to the projector and knowing where the
microphones are.
            </para>
            <para>
It is important that if you have this role that you show up during the setup period to understand the equipment.
The first shift will work with the presenters and first presentations. The next shifts will continue on supporing
the presenters.
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Requirements</title>
                  <para>
On paper this role seems super technical. To be successful you need to understand how to connect a laptop to
a projector and share the desktop.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check-in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will get you set up.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
                  <qandaset defaultlabel='qanda'>
                        <qandaentry>
                              <question>
                                    <para>
On what operating systems should I know how to share the desktop?
                                    </para>
                              </question>
                              <answer>
                                    <para>
OS X and Windows are needed. Other systems come up but the users tend to trend more tech savvy and will be able to
get the connection established with minimal assistance.
                                    </para>
                              </answer>
                        </qandaentry>
                  </qandaset>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
      	<title>Cleanup</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar | minnedemo
            </para>
      	<para>
The Cleanup role is there to help the core organizers with putting the venue back to the original state. This could
include putting away equipment and removing sinage.
      	</para>
      	<section>
      		<title>Start of Shift</title>
      		<para>
Please show up on time, check in with the volunteer coordinator, and be ready to help out!
      		</para>
      	</section>
      	<section>
      		<title>End of Shift</title>
      		<para>
When the tasks assigned to you are done you are welcome to check out the sessions.
                  </para>
      	</section>
      </section>

      <section>
            <title>Pop Czar</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar
            </para>
            <para>
The Pop Czars make sure that the tubs of ice are stocked with pop. They will need to be replenished from time to
time. Check on the tubs at the start of lunch, after lunch, and once in the afternoon. 
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will get you pointed in the right direction.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
            <title>Presenter Host</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnedemo
            </para>
            <para>
The Presenter Host is there to greet the presenters at the front door, bring them into the presentation space and
introduce them to the A/V Guide. If there are any questions the Presenter host can either try to answer them or
pass the question off to one of the organizers. 
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will introduce you to the A/V guide and give you a brief tour for the space.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
      	<title>Registration</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar | minnedemo
            </para>
      	<para>
Registration checks people in, gets nametags, gives out shirts, and food/beverage tickets.
      	</para>
            <section>
                  <title>Requirements</title>
                  <para>
For our events we use a smart device application for check-in. You will need to bring an Android or iOS device that is able to
run the Eventbrite door application and connect to the internet via a mobile or WiFi connection. If you do not have a suitible
device contact the Volunteer Coordinator and we will try to locate a device that can be used.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Before the Event</title>
                  <para>
Document the process for going out and pulling down the Eventbrite application to facilitate check-in.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
What should be done at the start of the shift.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
      	<title>Setup: General</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar | minnedemo
            </para>
      	<para>
Setup arrives before the event and readies the venue for the event which could include setting up tables, the presentation area, and sinage.
      	</para>
            <section>
                  <title>Before the Event</title>
                  <para>
There is no preperation that needs to happen for the Setup role.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
What should be done at the start of the shift.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
            <title>Setup: Video</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar
            </para>
            <para>
Help the videographers bring in equipment and set it up in the many rooms.
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check-in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will introduce you to the videographers.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
            <title>Snack Master</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar
            </para>
            <para>
The Snack Master reigns suppreme over placing snacks out before the Happy Hour. 
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will get you pointed in the right direction.
                  </para>
            </section>
      </section>

      <section>
            <title>Video</title>
            <para>
Applies to: minnebar
            </para>
            <para>
Each person a a video shift is assigned a few of the rooms and is expected to make sure that there is enough room to
record and that the camera is pointed at the person who is speaking. If there is a problem that you are able to not
fix you should bring it to the attention of the minne* organizers.
            </para>
            <para>
The work for the Video shift is done before each session of a shift. After the checks have been done you will be able
to attend sessions.
            </para>
            <section>
                  <title>Start of Shift</title>
                  <para>
Check-in with the Volunteer Coordinator who will assign you a set of rooms for your shift.
                  </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
                  <section>
                        <title>A question</title>
                        <para>
A reasonable answer to the question.
                        </para>
                  </section>
            </section>
      </section>

</chapter>